Guide to the Enfield Methodist Episcopal Church records, 1867-1987.
Enfield Methodist Episcopal Church records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Enfield Methodist Episcopal Church records, 1867-1987.
6811
N.Y.) Enfield Methodist Episcopal Church (Enfield
2 cubic feet.
Correspondence, Diaries, Financial Records, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Church Record, 1867-1891,1882-1904, 1897-1926; Recording Steward's Book, 1901-1910; Sunday School records, 1896-1897, 1905; financial records, 1927-1965; membership register, 1965, publications, 1970s; and correspondence and newsletters, 1970s-1987.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
The Methodist Episcopal Church was part of the Ulysses circuit, and its pastors and class leaders attended the circuit quarterly conference meetings. The Ulysses circuit embraced charges, classes, and societies at Trumansburg, Mecklenburg, Enfield, Covert, Jacksonville and McIntyre's Settlement. In 1833 the circuit was divided into East and West sections, or Ulysses and Enfield circuits.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Church Record, 1867-1891,1882-1904, 1897-1926; Recording Steward's Book, 1901-1910; Sunday School records, 1896-1897, 1905; financial records, 1927-1965; membership register, 1965, publications, 1970s; and correspondence and newsletters, 1970s-1987.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Enfield Methodist Episcopal Church (Enfield, N.Y.)
Subjects:
Methodist Episcopal Church--New York (State)--Enfield.; Church records and registers--New York (State)--Enfield.; Sunday schools--New York (State)--Enfield.
Places:
Tompkins County (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.; Enfield (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Historical items 1875-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Annual report statistics, misc. 1931-1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Bulletin, historical items, clippings, misc. 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Guestbook 1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Enfield - Misc. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Misc. + Membership list - Enfield 1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Enfield 1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Misc. certificates, clipping, photographs 1995-2005 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Enfield minutes 1958-1978 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
- Reports 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Memberships correspondence 1970-1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Newsletters 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Conference reports 1967-1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Yearbook 1976 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Sunday School record book 1896-1897 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Sunday School record book 1905-1906 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Sunday School 1956-1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Financial Secretary record book 1927-1930 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Financial Secretary record book 1932-1934 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Financial record book 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Financial record book 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Financial record book 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Financial record book 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Check book 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Account book 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Account book 1965 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Stewardship + finance 1967-1973 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Finances 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Church Record of Enfield Circuit 1967-1895 (Box 2)
- The Church Record of Enfield Centre Methodist Episcopal Church 1891-1902 (Box 2)
- Recording Steward's Book. Enfield + Kennedy's Charge 1901-1936 (Box 2)
- Members of Enfield Centre, Kennedy's Corners, Enfield Falls 1905-1937 (Box 2)
- Financial Secretary book 1953-1954 (Box 2)
- Finances 1957-1958 (Box 2)
- Official Membership Register and Church Record Enfield Methodist Church 1964-1970 (Box 2)
- Official Financial Secretary's Record 1964-1966 (Box 2)
- Official Financial Secretary's Record 1966-1967 (Box 2)